Wait for me
Hurry up!
Wait up!
Wait for me
Come on!
Guts!
（魔物）王子よ
Prince
我らが許されざる者どもの王子よ
Prince of we
The Unforgiven
ご拝謁たまわりたく…
We seek an audience with you
（ボイド）いずれ 彼の地で
会いまみえようぞ
We shall meet.
in that time. at that place.
我らが眷属(けんぞく) 渇望の福王よ…
We are kinsmen.
oh blessed King of Longing.
（司祭１）今度はシェトで
目撃されたそうですぞ
It was seen in Chet this time
（司祭２）何と…
What?!
（司祭３）こうも各地で
怪異が続発するとは―
What kind of evil do these
strange occurrences portend?
いったい何の凶兆でしょう
（司祭４）
法王庁が調査団を派遣するとか…
The Holy See is dispatching
a commission of inquiry to investigate
（司祭１）おお ついに
法王庁までもが動き出したか
So even the Holy See
is taking action
（ジュドー）
あまり根をつめるなよ
Don't overdo it
この上 お前まで倒れられたら…
We can't have you
collapsing on us
（キャスカ）わかってる
I know
リッケルトが戻った
グリフィスの居場所がわかったぞ
Rickert is back
He found out where
they're keeping Griffith
じゃ… じゃあ！
Then Then!
焦るな
Don't be hasty
（キャスカ）でも…
But
みんな もう限界だ
Everyone's reached their limit
こうして１年も
逃げ回ってるんだ
We've been running for a year
疲労だってピークだ…
We're all completely exhausted
But it's not like we can
take action immediately
だからって 今すぐどうにか
できるわけじゃないだろ
とにかく今は休め
Right now, you have to rest
Thanks
ありがとう
敵襲！
Enemy raid!
Was Rickert followed?
（コルカス）リッケルトめ
つけられやがったな！
（シラット）よくぞかわした
That was a nice move
I must hand it to the highly touted
female commander
さすがは噂に高い 鷹の団の女首領
of the Band of the Hawk
だが どのような戦も
大将首をあげた時点で勝敗は決まる
But in any kind of battle,
the moment the leader's head
is taken
is the moment the outcome
is decided
何！？
What?!
いったい 何だこいつら！
What the hell is he?!
No ordinary foe, that's for sure!
ただの敵じゃねえぞ！
キャスカ！
Casca!
（シラット）勝負あった
I win
剣を捨て部下どもに
降伏するよう命令するならばよし
Tell your men to put down
their swords and you'll live
でなければ このまま
素っ首 斬り落とす
Otherwise,
I'll cut your head off right now
みっつ数える 選べ
Now choose on the count of three
ひとつ
One
ふたつ
Two
Three!
みっつ！
（ガッツ）よっつ！
Four!
大道芸人相手に
へばってんじゃねえ
Don't let this street performer
tire you out
ピリッとしろよ 千人長
Pull yourself together Commander
Guts!
（リッケルト）ガッツ！
What?!
何だと？
（ガストン）
隊長！ 帰ってきてくれたんすね！
Captain! You came back!
（ガッツ）オラ！
へたりこんでるヒマはねえぞ
C'mon! Stop sitting around!
ここは俺に任せて
お前は自分の仕事をしろ
I'll take care of this
You go and do your job
行け
Go
Stay back and don't interfere
（シラット）
下がれ 邪魔をするな
こいつは私が殺す
He's mine
迅雷(じんらい)のごとき この刃
その身で受けよ！
This blade of thunder
will strike you down!
てえい！
おおらあ！
What-?!
Why you!
うぬれぇ
Master Silat!
（敵兵）シラット様！
撃て
Fire!
Fall back for now
（シラット）一旦 退くぞ
Casca!
（ガッツ）キャスカ！
（団員１）
負傷者には手を貸してやれ
（団員１）誰かいないか
大丈夫か？
（ガッツ）
何！？ グリフィスが…？
What?
Griffith was?!
（ジュドー）ああ
お前が出て行った次の日の話さ
Yeah, it happened the day
after you left
（コルカス）ヘッ！ ミッドランドの
救世主と謳われた俺たちが―
One day, we're hailed as
the saviors of Midland
一夜明けたらお尋ね者さ
貴族の夢もみんなパア
and in a single night,
we're branded criminals
So much for becoming a noble
お前にゃ
どうでもいいことだろうがな
But I guess you couldn't
care less about that
だが俺は 認めねえぞ
I'm not accepting you back
一番大変な時にいなかった野郎を
仲間なんて思わねえからな
Not some bastard who wasn't here
when he was needed most
He's not my comrade
構えろ
On guard
What?
Hey, wait!
（ガッツ）ちょっと待て！
今の殺気こもってたぞ
You totally tried to kill me just now!
おい キャスカ！
H-Hey, Casca!
Don't look down on me!
なめるな 剣を抜け！
Draw your sword!
相変わらず
ムチャクチャなヤツだな
You're reckless as ever
理由を言え
What's your problem?
（キャスカ）お前のせいだ…
It's your fault
（キャスカ）
お前がすべて… 壊した
You ruined everything
お前のせいだ！
It's your fault!
グリフィスも鷹の団も
お前がめちゃくちゃにした！
Griffith and the Band of the Hawk
You destroyed it all!
俺が？ 何で
Me? Why?
そこまでバカか お前は！
How stupid are you?!
You!
グリフィスが欲しがったのは
お前だけだ！
The only one Griffith wanted
was you!
お前だけがグリフィスの
隣にいたんだ！
You were the only one
close to Griffith!
お前がグリフィスを弱くした！
You made Griffith weak!
グリフィスは…
Griffith
Griffith's
no good without you!
お前がいなきゃ ダメなんだ！
（ガッツ）そんなはずねえ
That's not true
あいつはグリフィスなんだぜ…
We're talking about Griffith here
Griffith
あのグリフィスが…
離せ！ 血が…
Let go! You're bleeding
（ガッツ）俺は…―
I just did my own thing
自分のことをやっただけだ…
グリフィスと同じように
Just like Griffith
わかったから
離せ バカ！
All right, I get it!
Let go, you fool!
私はグリフィスの
I wasn't able to
become Griffith's sword
剣(つるぎ)にも女にもなれなかった…
or his woman
本当はわかってたんだ
To be honest, I knew
私の入るすき間なんて
とっくになかったんだって…
I realized long ago that there was
no place for me in his heart
私が必死にやってきたのは―
But I refused to give up
because if I did,
そうでもしないと
自分が消えてしまいそうだったから
I thought I'd fade away
Casca
キャスカ…
But it's all right
でも もういい
私… 疲れちゃった
I'm tired
あとは お前がやれ
You do the rest
Damn it! What the hell
were you thinking?!
ったく何考えてんだ！
いいか てめえは金輪際
崖に近づくんじゃねえ
Listen! Never go near a cliff,
ever again!
I can't deal with being dragged
along again another time! Damn it!
二度も三度も引きずり
落とされたんじゃ たまんねえぞ
You took everything from me
（キャスカ）
私からすべてを奪ったヤツなのに
殺してやりたいと思ってるのに…
I feel like killing you right now
バーカ
Fool
Hey
（キャスカ）
いつもケガしてるな 私のせいで…
You're always getting hurt
because of me
いつも血 流してるな お前は…
You're always bleeding
バーカ…
Fool
（キャスカ）なあ…
Hey
Huh?
（キャスカ）グリフィスを
救出したら 出てくって
You're leaving after
we rescue Griffith?
ああ けじめだけは
きっちりつけたいんだ
Yeah I stick to my decisions
You should come with me
お前… 俺と来いよ
Huh?
（ガッツ）グリフィスを救出したら
俺と一緒に
Come with me after
we rescue Griffith
I don't know what the future holds
先のことはわからねえ…
でも
But
このままじゃ
俺はお前を抱き足りない
I can't get enough of you
You fool
バカ
この先 何百回も
何千回もお前を抱きたいと―
I want to have you
hundreds
今はそう思ってる
thousands of times from here on
バカ…
You fool
バカバカ言うな 自覚してる
Quit calling me a fool
I'm aware of that
（ガッツ）おい キャスカ
起きろ キャスカ！
Hey, Casca
Wake up, Casca!
（髑髏(どくろ)の騎士）
やはり歯車は回り始めたか…
I see the wheel has begun to turn
バカな 確かに後ろに
What? I'm positive
he was behind me
何だ てめえは！？
Who the hell are you?!
（髑髏の騎士）
心するがよい もがく者よ
Heed my words, you who struggle
これより後 貴様の上に―
Shortly, a rain of terror,
the likes of which
you cannot control,
人の身では決してあがない切れぬ
狂気の豪雨 死の嵐が吹き荒れる
shall descend upon you
A storm of death
だが心するのだ もがく者よ
But take heart, you who struggle
もがき 挑み 足掻(あが)く！
Resist, challenge,
and struggle more
それこそが
死と対峙する者の唯一の剣
That alone is the sword that
confronts death
ゆめゆめ忘れぬことだ
Do not forget these words
（ガッツ）
おっ おい 何のことだ！？ 待て！
H-Hey!
What was that all about?! Wait!
よく見つけたな こんな抜け道
How did you find this place?
（ジュドー）内通者がいるのさ
I had some help from the inside
（キャスカ）グリフィスを
救いたいと思っているのは―
It means we're not the only ones
who want to rescue Griffith
私たちだけじゃ
ないということだ
けどよ 城の連中が…
But insiders from the castle?
（シャルロット）
鷹の団の方ですか？
Are you with the Band of the Hawk?
I've waited for you
お待ちしておりました
本当に来てくださったのですね
You really did come
Princess?!
お姫さん！？
んじゃ内通者ってのは…
You're the help from the inside?!
はい 私です
Yes, it was me
（ガッツ）
この穴 どこまで続いてんだ？
How far down does this hole go?
遠い昔 今から千年ほども
前の話です
Many years ago
about a thousand years
During the age of wars
当時は戦乱の時代
Huh?
その動乱に
終止符を打つ者が現れました
Someone appeared
who put an end to the warring age
覇王ガイゼリック
The Supreme King Gaiseric
彼は大陸全土にわたる大帝国を
一代で築きました
He conquered all the regions
of the continent
and built an empire in
one generation
その素性は謎に包まれていますが
大変な戦上手で―
There's much mystery
surrounding him
But he was skilled in battle and
it's said that he always wore
a skull mask on the battlefield
戦いの際にはいつも髑髏を象(かたど)った
仮面をつけていたと言います
（ジュドー）
それなら聞いたことありますよ
I've heard the story of
the Skull King before
髑髏の王様の話
でも力に溺れた王様は
神様が遣わせた５人の天使に―
But the King became
drunk with power,
and God sent five angels after him
and destroyed his capital
都ごと滅ぼされてしまったって
４人じゃなかった？
Wasn't it four?
So what does that fairy tale
have to do with this hole?
で そのお伽話とこの穴が
どう繋がるんだ？
お伽話ではありませんわ！
少なくとも その都は実在したのです
It's not a fairy tale!
At least The capital did really exist
この縦穴の奥底に
Deep down at the bottom
of this tunnel
Oh boy
（ジュドー）あーあ…
グリフィス？
Griffith?
（シャルロット）グリフィス様！
Lord Griffith!
誰かいる！
Someone's there!
グリ…！？
Gri-
グリ… フィス？
Grif fith?
グリフィス！
Griffith!
手足の腱が切られてる
The tendons in his arms and legs
have been cut
舌も…
His tongue too
キャスカ 鍵だ！
Casca! The key!
キャスカ！
Casca!
（ガッツ）来るな！
Stay back!
来るんじゃねえ！
Don't come
Impossible
そんなはずねえ
This can't be Griffith!
これが あの…
グリフィスのはずがねえ…
（シャルロット）きゃあっ！
（拷問官）
お お前ら もう逃げられないど
Y-You can't escape now
鍵かけちまったからな イヒヒヒ！
I just locked the door
（ガッツ）おめえか
Was it you?
グリフィスをこんなにしたのは？
Did you do this to Griffith?!
（拷問官）やぁ
こんな綺麗なしと手にかけたの―
I've never laid a hand on
someone so handsome
オラ初めてだからなぁ
拷問にも何つーかこう
リキが入っただなぁ
It was torture,
but how can I put it
It gave me such a lift
First, I cut the tendons
in his arms and legs,
まず逃げ出さないように
手足の腱を切ってよ
so that he wouldn't try to escape
それからはメシと寝る時間以外は
皮を剥いだり 爪を剥いだり―
Then whenever he wasn't
eating or sleeping,
I peeled off his skin,
pulled out his nails,
put hot irons on him,
put boiling water on him
焼きゴテ当てたり 熱湯につけたり
もう１年間 オラたち
夫婦みてぇに付きっきりだ
Why, we've been inseparable like
husband and wife this past year
オラの自慢のコレクション
見てくれろ オラのお守り
Take at look at the best part
of my collection!
It's my lucky charm
舌だぁ そいつの キシシシ…
レロレロレロ～
It's his tongue
はがっ…
これから死ぬのに
二枚舌じゃ天国に行けねえぜ
You're gonna die now
You can't go to heaven
double-tongued
（拷問官）や やめれ レロレロ…
S-Stop!
ダメだな てめえの息はクサ過ぎる
地獄行きだな
Forget it
Your breath reeks too badly
You're going to hell
（拷問官）がああ～ ううう
あぶ… たしゅ たしゅけ…
H-Hewup
聞こえねえよ はっきり喋れ
Can't hear you Speak clearly
ぎゃあ～！
（隊長１）動くな！ 武器を捨てて
おとなしく投降しろ！
Don't move!
Now drop your weapons
and surrender quietly!
Guts, maybe we
should retreat for now
ガッツ ここは一旦…
Kill them! Kill them!
（隊長１）斬れ 斬れーっ！
（隊長１）何をしておる！ 撃て！
What are you doing?!
- Shoot!
- Y-Yes, sir!
行くぞ ガッツに遅れるな！
Don't fall behind Guts!
（国王）な 何だと！？
グリフィスを奪われただと！
W-What?!
Griffith was taken?!
Do not let them get away!
逃がすな！
絶対に逃がしてはならん！
Don't you dare let them get away!
（兵士）敵は少数だぞ！
There are only a few of them!
Miss Casca!
（使用人）キャスカ様
こっちです！
This way!
すまない
Thank you
へへ 救国の英雄のために
働けるなんて光栄ってもんです
I'm honored to be able to assist
our kingdom's heroes
（隊長２）門を閉めろ！
Close the gates!
急げ 急げ！
Hurry! Hurry!
絶対に反逆者どもを
通すでない！
Do not let the rebels through!
Understand?!
Aim for the horses! Shoot!
馬を狙え！ 撃て！
The fools
バカな…
突っ込んで来る気か！？
Do they intend to
force their way out?!
What are you doing, you fools?!
何をしている！？ バカ者！
（ガストン）急げ 急げ
Hurry! Hurry!
やったぞ
（シャルロット）グリフィス様
Lord Griffith
また会えますよね…
I hope we meet again
さっ 姫様 ん？
This way, Princess
（ガストン）正規軍だ
It's the regular army
About fifty
ざっと50… いや100騎はいるぞ！
No, a hundred!
（キャスカ）妙だな
Strange
近づいてこない…
Why aren't they approaching?
It's an ambush
待ち伏せだ
くそっ！
Sis, behind us too!
（ガストン）姐(あね)さん 後ろもヤバい！
お前たちは前へ来い
You guys, take the front
ガッツ ピピン 後ろを頼む
Guts, Pippin Cover the rear!
（隊長３）陛下に弓引く重罪人だ
絶対に逃がすな！
They are heinous criminals who
dare aim their arrows at the king
Do not let them escape!
馬がやられた
長くは持たないぞ！
The horse is hit!
It won't hold up much longer!
（ガッツ）キリがねえ！
Damn, there's no end to this!
（ジュドー）くそっ ここまでか…
Shit Is this it?
間に合ったか！
He made it in time!
Corkus!
コルカス！
フフ… 一度やってみたかった
I've always wanted to do this
よっしゃ 野郎ども！
All right, men!
Attack!
全軍 突にゅるれ～…
H-Hey, forget that
今のナシ ねえ
（団員たち）乾杯！
- Cheers!
グリフィスさえ戻ってくりゃ
こっちのもんよ
As long as Griffith is back,
victory is ours
鷹の団 完全復活っすね
The Band of the Hawk is
completely revived
Yeah We'll win, and win
and keep on winning!
おうよ また勝って勝って
勝ちまくってやるぜ
We should get a commission
with Chuder
今度はチューダーにでも
任官しますか
ミッドランドのヤツらに
一泡ふかせてやるか
That'll shock
those Midland bastards
そりゃいい ハハハ…
That's a great idea
（キャスカ）すまないな
すぐに交代を用意させる
Sorry I'll get someone to
relieve you right away
（見張り）
いえ 隊長こそ休んでください
It's all right
Please rest, Commander
ずっと働きづめじゃないですか
You haven't taken a break at all
お前たちに心配されたくないな
I don't want you guys to
worry about me
どうなんだ？ グリフィスは
How is Griffith?
俺は医者じゃないからな
詳しいことは…
I'm not a doctor,
so I can't really
お願い
Please
（ガッツ）グリフィス
Griffith
暑くねえか それ
Isn't that awfully hot?
取ったっていいんだぜ
２人しかいねえんだから
You can take it off
It's just the two of us
着けたいのか？
You want that on?
ハハハ… お前らしい
That's just like you
変わんねえな １年経っても
ここはまだ戦場だもんな
You haven't changed
A year's passed
I guess this is still a war zone
甲冑(かっちゅう) 着けなきゃ
始まらねえよな
You've gotta have armor on, right?
（ジュドー）それに 手も足も
腱ごと持ってかれてる
And they cut the tendons
on his arms and legs
立ち上がることも
剣を握ることも もう…
He can't stand or
swing a sword
I see
（キャスカ）そう
ジュドーから聞いた
Judeau told me
I see
そうか
Stop, you idiot!
おい 冗談だよな？
あのグリフィスが…
H-Hey, it's a joke, right?
About Griffith?
わあったよ 直接本人に聞く
Fine I'll just ask him myself
（ジュドー）無理だよ
（コルカス）ん？
It's no use
Griffith can't speak anymore
グリフィスは
もう話せないんだ
（団員たち）
グリフィスが… 何だと？
どういうことだ
本当なのか？
（コルカス）
ああ…！ 何だよ そりゃ
What the hell?!
Weren't we gonna
start all over again?
これからじゃ なかったのか
グリフィスが戻ってきて
全部これからじゃ なかったのかよ
Now that Griffith is back?
わけもわからねえうちに
罪人にされて―
They labeled us criminals
for no reason at all
１年間 虫けらみてえに逃げ回って
仲間も大勢殺されて
And for a year,
we've been on the run
We lost so many comrades
And yet
それでも グリフィスさえ
帰ってくりゃあって―
We kept our hopes up that
when Griffith returned
信じたあげくが… これかよ！
And now, this?!
What'll we do?
（団員１）どうするんですか
What are we supposed to do now?
（団員２）これから俺たち…
（団員３）
何とかならないんですか？
Isn't there anything we can do?
（団員４）キャスカ隊長！
Commander Casca
（団員５）鷹の団が
全滅したわけじゃないんだぞ
The Band of the Hawk
ain't dead yet
このままキャスカ隊長が…
If Commander Casca continues
Give me some time
（キャスカ）時間をくれないか
次の追っ手が来るまで
まだ時間があるはずだ
There should be some time
until the next enemy attack
それまで考えさせてくれ
Let me think it over until then
（ガッツ）おい 待てよ
考えるって お前どうするんだよ？
Hey, wait
What do you need to think over?
What were you about to
tell everyone just now?
（キャスカ）お前 さっきみんなに
何を言おうとしたんだ？
Huh?
自分で挑んだ戦のケリくらい
自分でつけろって…
That you have to finish
the battles that you start
（キャスカ）強いな お前は
You're so strong
Because one chooses to fight
自分で挑んだ戦だから
自分でやめられないこともあるだろ
one can't back out
その言葉を
今のグリフィスにも言えるのか？
Can you say those same words
to Griffith?
みんな弱いんだ
弱いから人や夢にすがってる
We're all weak
That's why we rely on
people and dreams
すがるものを
無くしてしまった人には―
And is there anything we can do for
someone who's lost what they rely on?
何かしてあげられるのかな
優しい言葉？ 厳しい言葉？
そばにいてあげること？
Should we be kind? Or strict?
Should we stay by their side?
私だって… 誰かに
そばにいてほしかった
Even I wanted someone to
stay by my side
What do I do?
どうすればいい？
私 どうすれば…
What am I supposed to do?
（ガッツ）俺だってわからねえよ
I don't know either
I'm going to go see Griffith
（キャスカ）
グリフィスの所に行ってくる
グリフィス 包帯 取り換えよ
Griffith I'm going to change
your bandages
So, what're you gonna do from now?
（ジュドー）
で お前どうすんの これから
また旅にでも出るのか
Set out on your travels again?
What about you, Judeau?
ジュドーは？
そうだなあ
Well, let's see
Maybe I'll recruit
the guys who stay
居残った連中誘って
盗賊でもおっぱじめるか
and form a band of thieves
そうすりゃグリフィス一人くらい
面倒見れるだろう
Then at least,
we can look after Griffith
だったら俺も
Then I'll join you
お前はもう抜けた人間だろう
それより今度こそキャスカ連れてけよ
You already left us
But this time, take Casca with you
Huh?
（ジュドー）あいつは…
今度こそ連れていかないと
You have to take her this time
Or else
あいつは…
She'll
You
お前
Captain
（ガストンたち）隊長 隊長
- Captain
Are you gonna disappear without
a word again like the last time?
（ガストン）また前ん時みたいに
ふらっと行っちまうつもりですかい？
そん時ゃ あっしらも
ご一緒させてくださいよ
If you are,
please take us with you
切り込み隊
みんなで決めたんです
We decided together as raiders
あっしら まだまだやれますぜ
We've still got a lot left in us
傭兵だって何だって
As mercenaries, or whatever
隊長さえいてくれりゃ
As long we have you, Captain
- Captain
- Hey, guys
（団員たち）隊長 頼んます 隊長！
- Please, Captain!
- Captain
隊長
俺たちみんな
家族みてえなもんでしょう？
We're all like family, right?
If we're wanted criminals
wherever we go,
どこ行ってもお尋ね者なら
一緒がいいです
let's stick together!
隊長さえいてくれたら
何とかなります 俺たち
As long as you're with us,
we can manage!
（隊員）
ねえ 隊長！ お願いしますよ！
Right, Captain? Please!
隊長！
- Captain
お願いします 隊長
- Please, Captain!
- Captain
Rickert is scouting ahead and
（キャスカ）リッケルトが先行して
国境を越える道を探してる
looking for roads to take us
across the border
カロニア山脈に
知り合いがいるって…
He knows some people
in the Caronia Mountains
How strange This is
あ あれ？
おかしいな こんな…
ずいぶん うまくなったと
思ったのに…
I thought I had the hang of it
ダメだな 私って…
I'm so hopeless
Oh
S-Sorry
ご ごめん
毛布の代わり持ってくる…
I'll get another blanket
Huh?
What? Griffith?!
何！？ グリフィス
グリフィ…
Grif
グリフィス… やめて！
Griffith
Stop!
（ガッツ）キャスカ
Casca?
（キャスカ）ガッツ…
Guts
グリフィスは？
How's Griffith?
うん… 今眠ったところ
Yeah He just went to sleep
（ガッツ）どうかしたか？
What happened?
What do you mean?
（キャスカ）な… 何がだ
（ガッツ）
おい何だよ どうかしたか…
Hey, what is it? What's the matter?
（キャスカ）
違うんだ これは何でも…
It's not what you think
It's nothing
Then why are you crying?
何でもないのに泣くのかよ
グリフィスがどうかしたのか
Did something happen with Griffith?
やめて 違うんだ！
Stop it!
It's not what you think!
（ガッツ）お おい…
H-Hey
I'm sorry, I can't go
（キャスカ）ごめん 行けない
Huh?
（キャスカ）私…
お前と行けない…
I can't go with you
あのグリフィスが
あんなにやせ細って…
Griffith is so thin
あんなに軽く… あんなに震えて…
He's lost so much weight
he's constantly shivering
あの誇り高いグリフィスが…
Griffith who was
so proud and mighty
置いて行けない
今のグリフィスを…
I can't leave him
Not the way he is now
置いてなんて行けない
ごめん…
I can't leave him
I'm sorry
（ガッツ）俺も残る
I'm staying too
鷹の団に残って 俺も…
I'm staying with
the Band of the Hawk
プロムローズ館でのこと
覚えてる？
Do you remember what happened
at Promrose Hall?
Yeah
だったら お前は行かなくちゃ
Then, you have to go
If you are Griffith's equal
お前がグリフィスの対等の者なら
友達なら…―
If you are his friend
一人でも行かなくちゃ
You must go, even if it's alone
（少年グリフィス）
こんな所で何を脅えてるの？
What are you doing here?
Why are you so scared?
（少年グリフィス）行こうよ
まだ遊び足りないよ
Let's go. we're not done playing!
夕日はまだ沈んじゃいない
The sun still hasn't gone down!
- Griffith!
（キャスカ･ガッツ）グリフィス！
何だ 馬の暴走か？
What? Is the horse running wild?
You don't think Griffith
heard us just now?!
まさか グリフィスが今の話を！？
バカな！
這うのがやっとだ…
That's ridiculous
He can barely crawl
Let Judeau and the others know!
ジュドーたちに知らせてくれ！
わかった！
Got it!
（ガッツ）馬貸せ！
Lend me your horse!
ちくしょう！ ちくしょう！
Damn it! Damn it!
ちくしょう！
Damn it!
（グリフィス）
そう… 俺は少し休みすぎた
Yes
I rested a bit too long.
I've got to go.
もう行かなくちゃ この遊びは
まだ終わってはいないのだから…
I'm not done playing.
あの路地裏の石畳は
まだ続いているのだから…
The cobblestone path
in the back alley
Continues on
What is it?
何だ？
お おい… あれは
Hey look
（ガッツ）グリフィス！
Griffith!
グリフィス！
（グリフィス）来るな！
Stay away!
来るな！
何だ…！？
What is that?
（グリフィス）
今 お前に触れられたら…
If you touch me now.
I'll never
俺は二度と…
二度とお前を…
never again with you!
何だ？ あっ
What?!
（ガッツ）何が… 起こった…？
What
just happened?
どうなってる！？
What's going on?!
（団員たち）うわあ～
ここ どこなんだぁ！
Where are we?
W-What is all this?!
何だよ こりゃあ…！？
どっから現れた？
Where'd they come from?
（団員１）お 俺たち…
草原走ってたよな… なあ！？
W-Weren't we just crossing
the grassland?! Right? Right?!
H-Hey!
（団員２）お おい！ 足元見ろ！
Watch your step!
H-How could this be real?!
こんなことあるはずねえ！
こりゃ夢だ 俺たちゃ夢を見てるんだ
This is a dream!
We're dreaming!
Calm down!
（キャスカ）落ち着け！
Don't try to rationalize something
you don't understand!
わからないことは考えるな！
できることをやるんだ！
Do what you can do!
Form a tight formation,
take defensive positions!
円陣防御を組め
今 敵に襲われたら全滅だぞ！
If we're attacked now,
we're all dead!
Judeau! Corkus!
ジュドー！ コルカス！
ガストン！ ピピン！
Gaston! Pippin!
Do a count,
人数を確認して陣形を整えろ
（ガッツ）ったく大したタマだぜ…
- She's amazing
- then keep your positions!
（キャスカ）
クロスボウを持ってる者に
矢を渡せ！ ぐずぐずするな！
Arm those with crossbows!
- Stat!
- Griffith
グリフィス 立てるか？
Can you stand?
ベヘリット？
Behelit?
グリフィス… 大丈夫か？
Griffith Are you all right?
（異形たち）刻(とき)が来た…
The time has come
刻が来た…
大いなる夜祭の刻が…
The time has come for
the Great Nocturnal Festival!
216年に一度の宴の刻…
The feast that happens
once every 216 years!
蝕(しょく)が！
The eclipse!
蝕！？
Eclipse?
（団員１）何だ こいつら！？
What are these guys?!
W-When'd they appear?
（団員２）いつの間に…
来る！
They're coming!
来るぞ…
They're coming
おいでに なられる
Here they come
来る あの方たちが…
They are coming
They're coming
来るぞ…
来る…
Our masters The sovereign
of the supreme beings!
我ら超常たる者たちの王
（異形）４人の守護天使の降臨だ！
The advent of
the Four Guardian Angels!
Oh, Lady Slan! Rejoice!
（異形）おお スラン様！
（異形）スラン様！
Lady Slan!
（ユービック）キョホホ…
キョホホ…
今度は何よ！？
What now?!
W-What's happening?!
な 何だ
（ガッツ）神…
Gods
いや 悪魔？
No, demons?
（ボイド）よくぞ集った
Welcome
人の造りし
神ならざる神の子羊たちよ
Ye lambs of the ungodly god
born of man
この聖なる夜祭
存分に味わうがよい
Enjoy this sacred
nocturnal festival to the fullest
The Hawk
（ボイド）
因果律に選ばれし御子 鷹よ
honorable child consecrated
by the laws of causality
Thou art the chosen one
お前は選ばれし者
この刻 この地にあるように―
At this time, in this place
The one chosen by
the hand of the great god
大いなる神の御手により
定められし者
我らが眷属 渇望の福王なり！
We art kinsmen
O blessed King of Longing
（団員１）眷属…？
（団員２）そんな…
He's one of them? Griffith?
仲間？ グリフィスが？
He's like them?
（団員３）あいつらと同じ…？
Don't joke around
…ざけんな
That's ridiculous!
ふざけんじゃねえぞ！
ガッツ…
Guts
御子だと？ 眷属だと？
バカ言ってんじゃねえぞ！
Consecrated child? Kinsmen?
Cut the crap!
I've seen this guy naked!
こちとら こいつの裸だって
拝んだことあるんだ
And one thing for sure,
he ain't got a tail!
こいつにゃシッポの一本も
生えちゃいねえ！
（スラン）アハハ…
Such beautiful friendship
美しい友情だこと
You shall make for
an excellent sacrifice!
あなた さぞかし
よい生贄になることでしょうねえ
Sacrifice?
生贄？
Yes A suitable sacrifice so
that he may become a demon!
（スラン）そう 彼が
魔王になるための貴い生贄…
（ユービック）その真紅の
ベヘリットを手にした時から―
The moment you took
the Crimson Behelit in your hand,
you earned the right to
become a demon god
お前は魔王の資格を
得ていたのさ キョホホホ…
（スラン）それは我ら守護天使―
That is the Egg of the King
It enables one to be reborn
as one of us,
ゴッド･ハンドに
転生することのできる覇王の卵なの
the Guardian Angels, the Godhand
And you are all invaluable
sacrifices for the Angelic Advent
そして あなたたちは
天使降臨のための―
大切な生贄…
夢だ やっぱこりゃ夢だ
It's a dream, after all
You bastards You're gonna
change Griffith into a monster?
てめえらバケモノに
グリフィスを変えちまうだと？
In exchange for our lives?!
俺たちの命と引き替えに…
Not quite
（スラン）少し違うわね
それをするのは彼の意志
It will be of his own will
He will offer you all
as sacrifices
彼があなたたちを
生贄に捧げるの…
（ガッツ）そんなわけねえだろ
That's impossible
No way!
そんなことあるはずが…
（ボイド）
すべては因果の流れの中に
All lies within
the currents of causality
Now is the time
for the Invocation of Doom
これより降魔の儀を執り行う
The Invocation of Doom!
御子を祭壇へ！
Bring the child to the altar!
Guts, Griffith!
ガッツ！ グリフィス！
Are you afraid?
One such as yourself?
（ボイド）
恐ろしいか？ お前ほどの者が
Of extraordinary beings
such as us?
超常の者としての我らがか？
それともお前が
これからたどる未来か？
Or perhaps of the future
that you will follow?
（ユービック）未来に至る前に
今一度 知るがいい
Before we enter the future
Let's return once to
the foundation of your past
お前自身を…
My. my
（占い師の老婆）
やれやれ… 本当にうるさい子だね
Such a noisy boy.
一体 何を騒いでいるんだい？
What's all this racket?
（グリフィス）だって お婆さん
人がこんなに死んでるんだよ！
But old woman
There are so many dead people!
あんたが したことじゃないか
This is all your doing.
全部あんたがあの城に行くなんて
言い出さなきゃ―
All of this
If you had never said that
you were going to that castle
みんな死なずに
すんだんだよ！
no one would have died!
そんな… 僕は誰にも
無理について来いなんて…
That's
I didn't force anyone
to come with me.
Silence!
おだまり！
あんたは知っていたはずだよ
You should have known.
You knew what kind
of place this is.
ここがどんな所か
あんたは知っていたはずだ
知っていた？
I knew?
Yes.
（老婆）ああ そう
The only way to get to that castle
is to step over all these corpses.
あの城に行くには その屍を
踏みしだいて行くしかないんだよ
Otherwise. you will simply turn
into a corpse as well!
さもなければ あんたも
屍になるだけさ
I... I...
僕は… 僕は…
Foolish boy!
（老婆）バカだね この子は…
If you were going to have regrets.
you should never have wished it.
後悔するくらいなら 最初から
望まなければ よかったのに…
路地裏から見上げるだけで
どうして満足できなかったんだい！
Why couldn't you be satisfied
with gazing at the castle
from the alleys?
Yes
（グリフィス）
そう… 僕は知っていた
I knew.
And yet
なのに…
（グリフィス）詫びることはできない
いや 詫びはしない…
I cannot say I'm sorry.
No. I will not.
詫びてしまえば
悔やんでしまえば―
If I apologize
If I regret it'll all be over.
すべて終わってしまうから
I'll never get to reach that place.
あそこには もう
届かなくなってしまうから…
（ユービック）
そう それがお前だ！
Yes
That is you!
That was an illusion?
（グリフィス）今のは幻…？
幻などではない…
It wasn't an illusion
That was the reality
within your conscious realm
それはお前の
意識界における… 真実！
The truth!
（ボイド）天空の城めざし
頂に屍を積み続ける
Eyeing the castle in the heavens
Taking it by piling up
corpses endlessly
That is you
それが お前だ
（スラン）そして…―
And
今 あなたの
路地裏の道は途切れた
And now, your back alley path
has been closed
But behold
でも見なさい
Those who have flown with you
共に飛び続けてきた鷹の翼たち
The Band of the Hawk
血生臭い旅路の果てに
最後にあなたに残されたもの…
Reeking of blood
The ones left to you
until the very end of the road
そして あなたは生きていける
Thus, you will be able
to keep on living
Buried under the ruins
of your dream
夢の残骸に埋もれて…
（グリフィス）夢の残骸…
Ruins of my dream?
（ボイド）積み上げるがよい
お前に残されたすべてを…
Pile them up
All that has been left to you
一言 心の中で唱えよ
“捧げる”と
Chant the words "I sacrifice"
in your heart
And you shall be granted
raven-black wings
さすれば頂より 天に飛び立つ―
漆黒の翼を授からん！
upon which you shall soar
to the heavens
Griffith!
（ガッツ）グリフィス！
Yes
（グリフィス）そう…
何千 何万という敵味方の中で―
Among the thousands.
the tens of thousands of friend and foe
唯一 お前だけが…―
You are the only one
who made me forget my dream.
俺に夢を忘れさせた…
捧げる
I sacrifice
Griffith!
グリフィス！
The threads bundled by the laws
of causality have now been bound
（ボイド）因果律により
束ねられし糸は…―
今 結ばれた…
The promised time has come
約束の刻 来たれり！
Wha-?!
（ボイド）今 お前たちに
刻まれたものは 生贄の烙印
You have been engraved
with the brand of sacrifice
それを刻まれた者の生命は
その血の最後の一滴―
The lives of those engraved,
to the last drop of blood
断末魔の苦悶までも
新しき闇の子の―
To the moment of agonizing death,
will become sustenance for
the new child of darkness
命の糧となる
- Pippin!
- Run!
ピピン！
（ピピン）逃げろ！
Go! Run! Run away
You must survive!
行け！ 逃げて 逃げて…
お前は生き残れ！
何を言って…
What are you saying?!
What are you doing, Judeau?!
Let me go! Pippin is!
何をするんだ
ジュドー放せ！ ピピンが！
ぬおおっ！
（キャスカ）ピピン！
Pippin!
Judeau, turn back!
ジュドー戻せ
見殺しにする気か！？
We can't just let him die!
No!
（ジュドー）ダメだ！ 今はお前が
俺たちの大将なんだ
You are our general now
You must survive this
生き延びるんだ 大将が生きてりゃ
鷹の団は終わりじゃない
As long as the general lives,
the Band of the Hawk lives!
As if As if we'll die like this!
こんなのが俺たちの
終わりであってたまるか！
Until the absolute end
最後の最後まで足掻いて足掻いて
足掻きまくってやるんだ！
we'll struggle and fight,
and keep fighting our way through!
ここが合流地点か…
This is the rendezvous point
（髑髏の騎士）いやーっ！
（ゾッド）フン やはり現れたか
千年我らに仇なす貴様だ
So you appeared, after all
Well, you've been our foe
for a thousand years
この機を逃すはずが
ないとは思っていたが
I knew you wouldn't miss
this opportunity
So you were given the command
to guard the gate
（髑髏の騎士）
お前が門番を仰せつかったと
いうわけか 不死者よ
Immortal one
俺は らんちき騒ぎなどに
興味はない
I don't like merrymaking
You should know, my old friend
わかっているだろう
古き宿敵(とも)よ
隊長…
ぐはっ
アハハ… アハハハ
（コルカス）
ヒヒ 夢だ… 夢に決まってる
It's a dream
It has to be a dream
こいつはタチの悪い夢なんだ
This is a bad dream
I'm just drunk at the usual pub
いつもの酒場で
呑みつぶれただけなんだ
Someone
Hurry up and wake me
誰か… 早く俺を起こしてくれ
ジュドー ピピン リッケルト
そこにいるんだろう？
Judeau Pippin Rickert
You're there, right?
Please help me!
なぁ… 頼むよ！
A woman in hell?
地獄に女かよ…
Do me a favor
Don't wake me up now
頼むから今は…
起こすんじゃねえぞ
ちくしょう どうして俺って
ヤツはよう… ちくしょう
Damn it
How is it that a guy like me?
Damn it!
待ってろ グリフィス！
今 助け出してやるからな
Hang on, Griffith!
I'll get you out of there real soon!
邪魔すんな！
Get out of my way!
Save him?
There will be no such thing
助けるなんて お門違い
これは本人が望んだこと
This is his wish
You heard it too
あなたも聞こえたでしょう
彼は確かに…
He definitely
（ガッツ）黙れ！
Shut up!
言うわけないんだよ
あいつが そんなこと！
He'd never say it!
He'd never!
Griffith is my
グリフィスは俺の… 俺の！
He's my!
（キャスカ）ジュドー
Judeau!
ジュドー！
Fool! Move! You're gonna!
バカ どけ！
このままじゃ お前！
（キャスカ）どうして…
Why?
Casca
キャスカ…
Did I get him with my knife?
（ジュドー）
当たったか 俺のナイフ
Yeah, you got him
ああ 当たった 殺(や)ったぞ
Now go
（ジュドー）さあ… 行けよ
What're you saying?!
何言ってるんだ！ 最後まで
足掻くって言ったのは お前だろ！
You just said we'll keep struggling
until the end!
Stand by your words
自分の言ったことに
責任を持て！ さあ立て！
Now, on your feet!
Unlike Guts, I'm kinda fragile
（ジュドー）
ガッツと違って 華奢(きゃしゃ)なんでな…
（キャスカ）
減らず口をたたくな！
Don't get wise and shut up!
口だけですからね 俺は
That's all I'm good at
まったく 口を動かす…
- If you have time to move your mouth
- Yeah
（ジュドー）ほんと…―
- I always thought I was
- Move your legs! If you can't walk
自分じゃもっと器用なヤツだと
思ってたんだけどなぁ…
- more of a smooth talker than this
- I'll carry you if I have to!
Judeau
ジュドー… ダメだよ 私
I can't do it
（グリフィス）
ここは どこだ…
Where am I?
All their deaths are piercing through me.
みんなの死が
突き抜けてゆく…
不思議だ 何も感じない…
It's strange
I don't feel a thing.
My mind is overflowing with memories.
記憶が あふれ出てゆく…
Why?
なぜだ… なぜ人は…
Why do people?
Yes.
そうだ だから 俺は…
That's why I
（ガッツ）いないのか…
生きてるヤツは いないのか！
Isn't there anyone left
alive?
Anyone?!
Casca!
キャスカ！
Judeau!
ジュドー！ ピピン！
コルカス！
Pippin! Corkus!
切り込み隊 返事をしろ！
Raiders!
Answer me!
Gaston
ガストン…
Pippin!
ピピン！
生きてたのか！ ピピン
Pippin! You're alive!
Pippin!
グフフ…
Why you!
貴様ら…
貴様らっ！
You bastards!
（ユービック）誕生だ！
The birth
（スラン）五人目の福王
The Fifth Blessed King
（コンラッド）新たなる魔王
The New Demon King!
（ボイド）我らに連なりし
魔名(まな)を冠する 新しき眷属
Our new kinsman
to wear the mantle of evil
The Wings of Darkness
Femto!
闇の翼 フェムト
グリフィ…
Grif
What're you doing?
何してやがる…
てめえ 何してやがんだ！
You bastard!
What the hell are you doing?!
Grif fith?
グリ… フィス？
ぐおおっ！
Fool What can a mere human do?
（ユービック）愚かな
人間ごときに何ができよう
He is an existence that
has transcended humanity
彼はもう
人間を超越した存在…
ぐわっ！
D-Don't look
見ないで…
Such beauty
（スラン）美しい… 胸に迫るわ
It takes my breath away
Love hatred
愛 憎悪…
苦痛 快楽 生 死…
Pain pleasure life death
All are there
すべてがあそこに
This is to be human
これこそ人間 これぞ魔よ
This is to be evil
（髑髏の騎士）でやっ！
（ユービック）キョホホ…
面白い！ これは予想外だ
Interesting!
How unforeseen!
（スラン）ウフフ…
すべてを見通すことは不可能よ
We cannot predict everything
After all, we are not gods
私たちも また神では
ないのだから…
それともボイド
これも定められた運命の一つ？
But Void
Was this also destined?
Casca?!
キャスカ！？ ガッツ！？
Guts?!
In any case
（スラン）いずれにせよ
時はもう流れ始めてしまったわ
Time has already begun to flow
The fifth angel has been born
５人目の天使は
誕生してしまったのだから…
The time of darkness descends
（ボイド）闇の時が訪れる
あらゆる闇が
光を凌駕する時代
An age when every darkness
shall eclipse light
In time, man will call this
後に人は こう呼ぶだろう
暗黒時代と
The Age of Darkness
Hey, where're you all going?
みんな どこに行くつもりだ
Judeau!
ジュドー！ おい 止まれ！
Hey, stop!
行くんじゃねえ！
Don't go!
コルカス！ ピピン！
Corkus! Pippin!
ダメだ！ 引き返せ！
No!
Come back!
Don't go!
行くんじゃねえ！
Guts! You're up
（リッケルト）
ガッツ！ 目が覚めたんだね
（ガッツ）リッケルト…？
Rickert?
よかった
もうダメかと思ったよ
Thank goodness
I thought you wouldn't make it
４日もピクリとも
動かなかったんだから…
For four days
You didn't move or blink
ここは？
Where am I?
The hills by my home
（エリカ）私んちの裏山だよ
コードーっていうの
This place is called Ore Cave
ガッツ あの竜巻の中で
何があったの？
What happened inside the tornado?
竜巻…？
Tornado?
Say
（リッケルト）ねえ
グリフィス救出は どうなったの？
What happened to Griffith's rescue?
そのケガは？ 他のみんなは？
How'd you get hurt?
What happened to everyone?
ねえ 一体何があったのさ
Tell me what happened!
キャスカは…
キャスカはどこだ！
Casca Where's Casca?!
キャ… キャスカはその…
C-Casca is Well
（エリカ）キャスカお姉ちゃんなら
あそこだよ
Casca is over there
Casca
キャスカ…
It's me Guts
俺だ ガッツだ
イヤァ！
Nooo!
おい… 冗談はやめろ
もう終わったんだ キャスカ
Hey Quit fooling around
It's all over Casca!
We got out of there
and survived!
俺たち あそこから
生きて戻ったんだ！ キャスカ
Casca!
There, there
（エリカ）おーよちよち
おっかないお兄ちゃんですねー
What a scary man, huh?
ダメだよ ガッツ
キャスカお姉ちゃんをいじめちゃ
Naughty, Guts
Don't bully Casca
She doesn't remember
（リッケルト）覚えてないんだ
Not you or me
ガッツのことも 俺のことも
She's been like this
since she woke up
目が覚めてから
ずっとこうなんだ
There, there It's all right
ほーらよちよち
大丈夫よ…
そうね… よちよち
I know There's a good girl
Do I look funny?
おかしいか？
貴様ァ
Damn you! It's your fault!
貴様のせいだ
Draw your sword!
剣を抜けえ！
バーカ…
Fool
うおおおぉー！
（死霊）目だ… 俺のだ…
何だ？
What?!
（死霊）肝だ… 俺のだ
ニエ… ニエ…
Stop it!
離れろ
Get away!
やめろ！
（髑髏の騎士）気を強く持て！
さもなくばとり殺されるぞ
Steel yourself
Otherwise, you will be devoured
生贄の烙印…
それが闇の者どもを引き寄せるのだ
The Brand of Sacrifice
draws to it, those of darkness
Your body and every drop of blood
お前の肉体も
その血の最後の一滴までも―
has been given as an offering
to those of darkness
すべて闇の者に捧げられた
供物なのだ
それが烙印を受けし者の定め
That is the destiny of those
who receive the Brand of Sacrifice
The Struggler indeed
（髑髏の騎士）
まさに もがく者よ…
要するに こいつは戦だ
いつもと何も変わっちゃいねえ…
So it just means it's another battle
Nothing's changed from before
何も！
Nothing
（ジュドー）お前 今度こそ
キャスカを連れてけよ
But this time. take Casca with you.
（コルカス）ケッ！ 出たよ
人斬りバカが！
There he is. the bloodthirsty goon!
If you are Griffith's equal
（キャスカ）お前がグリフィスの
対等の者なら 友達なら…―
If you are his friend
一人でも行かなくちゃ
You must go. even if it's alone.
Who is that crying?
（グリフィス）誰だ…
泣いているのは… 誰だ？
Who?
Tears?
涙？
The last that
俺が流した…
I shed.
最後の…
（ガッツ）ハァ ハァ ハァ